const questions = [
  {
    id: '1',
    question: "which of the following rivers is the longest in the world?",
    options: {
      option1: "Mississippi River",
      option2: "Amazon River",
      option3: "Nile River",
      option4: "Yangtze River",
    },
    answer: "Nile River",
  },
  {
    id: '2',
    question: "One of the following persons was once the president of the United States of America?",
    options: {
      option1: "Condoleezza Rice",
      option2: "Thomas Jefferson",
      option3: "Bill Gates",
      option4: "Jeff Bezos",
    },
    answer: "Thomas Jefferson",
  },
  {
    id: '3',
    question: "who invented the telephone?",
    options: {
      option1: "The Wright Brothers",
      option2: "Bill Gates",
      option3: "Elon Musk",
      option4: "Alexander Graham Bell",
    },
    answer: "Alexander Graham Bell",
  },
  {
    id: '4',
    question: "one of the following is not the name of an ocean",
    options: {
      option1: "Indian Ocean",
      option2: "Atlantic Ocean",
      option3: "Pacific Ocean",
      option4: "Peak Ocean",
    },
    answer: "Peak Ocean",
  },
  {
    id: '5',
    question: "what part of speech is the word 'beautiful'?",
    options: {
      option1: "Noun",
      option2: "Adjective",
      option3: "Pronoun",
      option4: "Preposition",
    },
    answer: "Adjective",
  },
  {
    id: '6',
    question: "the most populous black nation on Earth is?",
    options: {
      option1: "South Africa",
      option2: "Kenya",
      option3: "Nigeria",
      option4: "Egypt",
    },
    answer: "Nigeria",
  },
  {
    id: '7',
    question: "Who was the first African American to become president of the United States of America?",
    options: {
      option1: "Barack Obama",
      option2: "Collin Powel",
      option3: "Ben Carson",
      option4: "Kanye West",
    },
    answer: "Barack Obama",
  },
  {
    id: '8',
    question: "How many years did Nelson Mandela spend in prison during the Apartheid in South Africa?",
    options: {
      option1: "26 years",
      option2: "27 years",
      option3: "28 years",
      option4: "29 years",
    },
    answer: "27 years",
  },
  {
    id: '9',
    question: "the idiomatic expression, 'the ball is in your court', simply means?",
    options: {
      option1: "To disobey instructions",
      option2: "To procrastinate ",
      option3: "The decision is yours to make",
      option4: "Your friends must always choose for you",
    },
    answer: "The decision is yours to make",
  },
  {
    id: '10',
    question: "if a traffic light shows red, what does it mean?",
    options: {
      option1: "Check your side mirror",
      option2: "Reverse your vehicle",
      option3: "Move your car",
      option4: "Stop your vehicle",
    },
    answer: "Stop your vehicle",
  },
  {
    id: '11',
    question: "What is the current world population?",
    options: {
      option1: "Over 8 billion",
      option2: "Over 7 billion",
      option3: "Over 6 billion",
      option4: "Over 5 billion",
    },
    answer: "Over 8 billion",
  },
  {
    id: '12',
    question: "in which continent of the world is China?",
    options: {
      option1: "Africa",
      option2: "South America",
      option3: "Asia",
      option4: "Europe",
    },
    answer: "Asia",
  },
  {
    id: '13',
    question: "in which continent of the world is Egypt?",
    options: {
      option1: "North America",
      option2: "Africa",
      option3: "Asia",
      option4: "Europe",
    },
    answer: "Africa",
  },
  {
    id: '14',
    question: "Ghana, a country in Africa, was formerly known as?",
    options: {
      option1: "The Platinum Coast",
      option2: "The Diamond Coast",
      option3: "The Silver Coast",
      option4: "The Gold Coast",
    },
    answer: "The Gold Coast",
  },
  {
    id: '15',
    question: "a person who flies a plane is called what?",
    options: {
      option1: "A Pilot",
      option2: "An Astronaut",
      option3: "An Engineer",
      option4: "A Driver",
    },
    answer: "A Pilot",
  },
  {
    id: '16',
    question: "who is an Astronaut?",
    options: {
      option1: "A person who treats people who are sick",
      option2: "Someone who is specially trained to travel into outer space aboard a spacecraft",
      option3: "Someone who makes other people laugh for a living",
      option4: "Another name for a pilot",
    },
    answer: "Someone who is specially trained to travel into outer space aboard a spacecraft",
  },
  {
    id: '17',
    question: "what is the full meaning of C.P.R ?",
    options: {
      option1: "Cardiopulmonary Rescue",
      option2: "Complete Police Report",
      option3: "Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation",
      option4: "Common Pulmonary Revival",
    },
    answer: "Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation",
  },
  {
    id: '18',
    question: "what is the full meaning of P.T.S.D ?",
    options: {
      option1: "Post Transplant Symptom Disorder",
      option2: "Pre Traumatic Stress Disorder",
      option3: "Post Transition Stress Disorder",
      option4: "Post Traumatic Stress Disorder",
    },
    answer: "Post Traumatic Stress Disorder",
  },
  {
    id: '19',
    question: "what is the full meaning of G.P.S ?",
    options: {
      option1: "Global Prisoners System",
      option2: "Global Positioning System",
      option3: "Global Planniing System",
      option4: "Global Platform System",
    },
    answer: "Global Positioning System",
  },
  {
    id: '20',
    question: "the following are the various parts of speech except?",
    options: {
      option1: "Paradox",
      option2: "Conjuction",
      option3: "Adverb",
      option4: "Verb",
    },
    answer: "Paradox",
  },
  {
    id: '21',
    question: "in Economics, a list of one's needs or wants in order of importance or priority is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Needs List",
      option2: "Scarcity",
      option3: "Choice",
      option4: "Scale of Preference",
    },
    answer: "Scale of Preference",
  },
  {
    id: '22',
    question: "in the famous Abraham Maslow's Hierarchy of Needs, which of the following is not a need?",
    options: {
      option1: "Rolex Watch",
      option2: "Physiological Need",
      option3: "Safety Need",
      option4: "Self-actualization",
    },
    answer: "Rolex Watch",
  },
  {
    id: '23',
    question: "the following are different sense organs except?",
    options: {
      option1: "The Nose",
      option2: "The Kidney",
      option3: "The Ear",
      option4: "The Eye",
    },
    answer: "The Kidney",
  },
  {
    id: '24',
    question: "the longest bone in the human body is?",
    options: {
      option1: "Ulna",
      option2: "Fibula",
      option3: "Femur",
      option4: "Tibia",
    },
    answer: "Femur",
  },
  {
    id: '25',
    question: "one of these is part of the Central Nervous System",
    options: {
      option1: "The Nose",
      option2: "The Arm",
      option3: "The Brain",
      option4: "The Leg",
    },
    answer: "The Brain",
  },
  {
    id: '26',
    question: "a leader is expected to possess the following qualities except?",
    options: {
      option1: "Empathy",
      option2: "Courage",
      option3: "Arrogance",
      option4: "Visionary",
    },
    answer: "Arrogance",
  },
   {
    id: '27',
    question: "a group of lions is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Pride",
      option2: "Courage",
      option3: "Arrogance",
      option4: "Herd",
    },
    answer: "Pride",
  },
   {
    id: '28',
    question: "a group of frogs is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Navy",
      option2: "Army",
      option3: "Airforce",
      option4: "Civilian",
    },
    answer: "Army",
  },
  {
    id: '29',
    question: "a group of bees is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Flock",
      option2: "Gathering",
      option3: "Swarm",
      option4: "Flying",
    },
    answer: "Swarm",
  },
  {
    id: '30',
    question: "a group of eagles is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Admission",
      option2: "Matriculation",
      option3: "Graduation",
      option4: "Convocation",
    },
    answer: "Convocation",
  },
  {
    id: '31',
    question: "a piece of land surrounded by water is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Off-shore",
      option2: "Low-land",
      option3: "Island",
      option4: "On-shore",
    },
    answer: "Island",
  },
  {
    id: '32',
    question: "the average adult human brain weighs about?",
    options: {
      option1: "1 pound",
      option2: "2 pounds",
      option3: "3 pounds",
      option4: "4 pounds",
    },
    answer: "3 pounds",
  },
  {
    id: '33',
    question: "the following are primary colours except one",
    options: {
      option1: "Purple",
      option2: "Blue",
      option3: "Red",
      option4: "Yellow",
    },
    answer: "Purple",
  },
  {
    id: '34',
    question: "a baby goat is known as?",
    options: {
      option1: "Child",
      option2: "Dad",
      option3: "Mom",
      option4: "Kid",
    },
    answer: "Kid",
  },
  {
    id: '35',
    question: "the 2022 FIFA U-23 world cup was hosted by which country?",
    options: {
      option1: "U.A.E",
      option2: "Israel",
      option3: "Qatar",
      option4: "Saudi Arabia",
    },
    answer: "Qatar",
  },
  {
    id: '36',
    question: "which country won the 2022 FIFA U-23 world cup?",
    options: {
      option1: "Argentina",
      option2: "France",
      option3: "Croatia",
      option4: "Morrocco",
    },
    answer: "Argentina",
  },
  {
    id: '37',
    question: "the capital city of Argentina is?",
    options: {
      option1: "Buenos Aires",
      option2: "Paris",
      option3: "Camberra",
      option4: "Washington D.C",
    },
    answer: "Buenos Aires",
  },
  {
    id: '38',
    question: "the Area of a rectangle with a length of 12 and a width of 4 is?",
    options: {
      option1: "16",
      option2: "8",
      option3: "48",
      option4: "3",
    },
    answer: "48",
  },
  {
    id: '39',
    question: "what is the answer to the expression 2(2 + 3) ?",
    options: {
      option1: "7",
      option2: "10",
      option3: "8",
      option4: "12",
    },
    answer: "10",
  },
  {
    id: '40',
    question: "solve the expression 2(4 + 3) - (8 + 9)",
    options: {
      option1: "-3",
      option2: "-6",
      option3: "-7",
      option4: "-4",
    },
    answer: "-3",
  },
  {
    id: '41',
    question: "how old was Queen Elizabeth II, former Queen of the United Kingdom, when she died?",
    options: {
      option1: "94",
      option2: "95",
      option3: "96",
      option4: "97",
    },
    answer: "96",
  },
  {
    id: '42',
    question: "what year did Nigeria gain independence from British rule?",
    options: {
      option1: "1960",
      option2: "1961",
      option3: "1962",
      option4: "1963",
    },
    answer: "1960",
  },
  {
    id: '43',
    question: "someone who hates women is referred to as a?",
    options: {
      option1: "Patriot",
      option2: "Hater",
      option3: "Bigot",
      option4: "Misogynist",
    },
    answer: "Misogynist",
  },
  {
    id: '44',
    question: "the practice of having more than one husband is known as?",
    options: {
      option1: "Monogamy",
      option2: "Embolism",
      option3: "Polyandry",
      option4: "Misogyny",
    },
    answer: "Polyandry",
  },
  {
    id: '45',
    question: "the scientific study of pre-historic people and their cultures using material remains is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Epistemology",
      option2: "Archeology",
      option3: "Sociology",
      option4: "Psychology",
    },
    answer: "Archeology",
  },
  {
    id: '46',
    question: "the famous book, 'The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People' was written by?",
    options: {
      option1: "Brian Tracy",
      option2: "John Mason",
      option3: "Stephen Covey",
      option4: "Barack Obama",
    },
    answer: "Stephen Covey",
  },
  {
    id: '47',
    question: "the type of family that consists of only the parents and their child or children is called?",
    options: {
      option1: "Disjointed Family",
      option2: "Nuclear Family",
      option3: "Atomic Family",
      option4: "Extended Family",
    },
    answer: "Nuclear Family",
  },
  {
    id: '48',
    question: "your brother's daughter would be referred to as your?",
    options: {
      option1: "Niece",
      option2: "Nephew",
      option3: "Cousin",
      option4: "Aunt",
    },
    answer: "Niece",
  },
  {
    id: '49',
    question: "your uncle's son would be referred to as your?",
    options: {
      option1: "Niece",
      option2: "Nephew",
      option3: "Cousin",
      option4: "Aunt",
    },
    answer: "Cousin",
  },
  {
    id: '50',
    question: "a young domestic cat is known as?",
    options: {
      option1: "Cub",
      option2: "Kid",
      option3: "Puppy",
      option4: "Kitten",
    },
    answer: "Kitten",
  },

];

//export default questions;
